The piece you requested. I had
it crafted by one of our best.
Oh, look at that.
Hmm. It's superb.
If it pleases you,
then I've succeeded.
But, sir, are you certain
it's the right thing? You know.
Because it's a bit solemn.
Looking to be
a wedding gift for my daughter?
Yes, that's all right.
It is the young
who must inherit our
history and move us forward.
But to tell the truth,
I did hesitate.
Huh? That girl at the exhibition
reminded me what her name was.
Are you talking
about Anne Halford?
Yes, precisely. If I could
just discern her whereabouts,
then not only would I learn more
about her and her confections,
but I'd see that pretty
fairy of hers too, huh?
Well, if you're wondering
about an. I just
saw her in town.
Here in Westhill.
It seemed like fate.
So I offered
to let her stay here with me.
But thank you, Hugh. But I'm
afraid I'll have to decline.
I'll feel better if I walk
on my own two feet.
So she refused an offer
from the Viscount
and an opportunity to study at
the prestigious Mercury Workshop.
How? Like her.
Well, then, where is she now?
Poor soul day is approaching
fast. So she's in Lewiston. Hmm.
In that case, perhaps I'll
cross paths with her.
Really? You're going there,
sir? Yes. I must go
and give counsel to His Majesty.
Counsel? The final spark.
You mean the Duke of Felix?
You just came in from Westall.
You went
and chose a difficult
place to do business.
That area is under the care
of the silver Sugar Viscount.
So the standard is quite high.
And on top of that,
most people would prefer to buy from
an artisan who's local. Right.
You're very knowledgeable, ma'am. And it's true.
I couldn't sell to anyone.
We'll have better luck there,
she said. Huh?
That's enough. Chale.
Maybe Ann was too optimistic,
but that's not a good
reason to call her stupid.
I did think it,
but I never said it.
The only one who did
that was you. Yeah.
But thinking it is just as bad.
I doubt that. And what's bad about
calling her stupid? Well, because.
The truth hurts.
What's the matter with you?
You got a problem
with humans and
fairies sitting
at the same table?
Listen,
as long as they pay their bill,
a customer is a customer to me.
Understood? If you don't like that, you're
free to leave. Sorry, dear.
But I do have to warn you,
it might be just as difficult
for you here in Lewiston
with pools all day coming up.
This is our busiest season.
I know, ma'am. I should know,
that's why I have to work hard.
Oh, I know, on the coast
of Rockwell Province,
down south of here,
there's a town
by the name of Felix.
Have you heard of it?
It's famous for trading. And the
royal family controls it. Right?
That's it.
Now, the Duke of Felix
is a man known as William
Auburn. Are you familiar?
These represent the family lines left behind
by our founding king, Cedric.
House Mills and House.
Chamber and house. Auburn
house Mills land were supposed
to be the heirs to the throne.
But when our current king,
Edmund the Second,
was only 12 years old, King
Edmund the First passed away,
and he was far too young
to rule. It's been 15 years.
Oh, I'm well aware. Chamber thought they
could take advantage of that.
So they tried to claim control. Then
the chamber rebellion, but thankfully.
You put an end to that with
the assistance of Thomas Orban?
Of course.
Truth be told,
what happened during that
uprising caused me to fear you.
You pulled House chamber out by the
roots and destroyed them all.
Though it was harsh,
your choice was understandable.
But then you went
so far as to try
to banish House Auburn despite what they'd
done for the royal family.
You took their land
and dismantled their armies.
This kingdom does not
need two rulers.
That was the lesson we learned.
Well be that as it may. Edmund
the Second chose to stop
accepting counsel from you.
He admired Thomas for his
warm heart and gentle nature.
That will
of his was quite mighty
for a child at only
12 years of age.
That's why House
Auburn was given Felax,
which was under
strict royal control.
Revenue goes to the royal family
and is proof of their loyalty.
Once a month
they must pay a visit
to Lewiston.
Those were the two conditions.
And now Thomas has passed on.
So it's
up to his son, William
to fulfill those conditions.
And I happen to know
the man personally.
He doesn't have evil intent.
He's intelligent and gentle.
Despite all that,
you still believe he
is the last spark of rebellion.
What if that spark is beginning
to smolder once more?
Soon it may grow into a blaze,
sending up smoke like a signal.
If that isn't a spark, then
what would you call it? Mercury.
So then, is Auburn truly. Trying
to find a new sugar artisan?
And you don't have
to be a master either.
You go stay at the castle,
and if the Duke
decides he likes
the peace you made,
they say he'll give you
a thousand crest reward.
Imagine. Wait, what?
A whole thousand.
Shocking, isn't it?
Impressing him is impressing
a descendant of none other
than King Cedric himself.
You'd earn great prestige
as a sugar artisan.
Everyone who prides
themselves on their skill
was just thrilled to hear
the news. So exciting.
A thousand crests are.
Felax of Rockwell Province.
It flourishes through trade with the continent.
It's Highland's greatest port town.
And yet all of that trade
wealth is devoured by Lewiston.
Each month,
the head of the house
must go there and seek
an audience with His Majesty.
How do you know all of that?
I've learned much in my life.
Human
affairs don't
usually interest me, but.
Have you brought
a sugar confection? Yes.
It's in the cargo hold. Good.
Then take it and go inside at
once. You two will wait here.
She's clear.
You may wait here. Oh, thanks.
Another artisan is here. Makes
sense. It is a thousand grass.
I can't help but wonder why
is this castle so bleak?
Everything is made of stone and
somehow. Hey! He's here! Huh?
There is no need to bow. My name
is William Alban,
the Duke of Felax.
Show me the pieces
you brought today.
You're free to go now,
but you will stay. But, sir.
God.
It's a very what inspired this?
The model for this piece is one
of my friends
who's traveling with me.
To be honest, it was supposed
to be a gift for him,
but he said eating it would
feel like cannibalism.
Very well.
I will allow you to stay.
Make me a sugar confection. One
that satisfies my expectations.
Yes, sir. Was there
something you had in mind?
Ah, beautiful.
This lady, she's a fairy, right?
You ought to give
form to the fairy
depicted in this portrait.
Can you do it?
I can. Perfect.
Del, show her to the workshop.
Right this way. Should you wish
to view this portrait again.
There are two towers near your
workspace in the east tower.
You'll find a collection
of paintings there
of this same fairy. Study them.
Right.
A friend, huh?
That was well said.
The Duke hates the practice
of enslaving fairies.
Is that why there aren't
any in the castle?
The two fairies
who accompanied you here
have already been shown
to the workshop.
Oh. Thank you.
That girl. Why does
the Duke want a sugar
confection of her? We're here.
Huh? Shell. Mithril.
You see that tower?
Three young artisans from
Radcliffe are staying there.
Do please keep out
of each other's way.
But why are there only three?
You just saw it firsthand.
The Duke's expectations
are high. Very high. Good luck.
A portrait of a fairy. A yes.
And she's incredibly beautiful.
He told me there
were even more
paintings of her in
the East Tower. Want to go see?
Now let's go upstairs first.
Did you see?
They've got beds
for three people up
there. Yes.
Real beds, soft beds.
That was fast. Hurry up. Huh?
The art. Let's go see it.
Come on. All right.
I'm sorry. I didn't
think you'd agree to go with me.
I'm just curious.
That smile's a bit much.
I know, I'm just happy.
It's Jonas. And.
Well, this is a surprise.
Uh, what
business do you have
at this castle?
Did you follow me here?
Are you looking for revenge?
Not exactly. No. Getting revenge for what
you did would be pleasant.
But I have better things to do.
Wait a minute.
Jonas. That's the same girl
who ruined the exhibition.
Yes, exactly.
She's the coward who set me up.
How can you stand there and say
I set you up when you were
the one who betrayed
me and stole my work?
She makes an interesting case.
But I saw the whole thing.
She tried to take credit
for someone else's piece.
You soured the king's
mood and cost
everyone a chance at the medal.
We can't excuse that.
After all, you've
insulted a representative
of the proud Radclyffe School.
Well, gentlemen.
What do you intend to do now?
You must have come
here because you
heard about the Duke of Felix.
But I deserve the glory and riches.
You'll fail like last time.
We both know I have more skill.
If I were you, I'd start
packing my bags to go home.
Honestly, Scarecrow. Calm down.
Let's go.
Is it done? Almost. Thanks
so much. Mythril pod. Huh?
You're such a big help when.
My greatness is multiplied
by intense effort.
Such are the results. Though. It's not
enough to repay that favor.
Oh, you don't need
to worry about that anymore.
Where did shall wander off to?
This
happens every time
you start working.
And he just saunters
off somewhere, huh?
It's hard to believe even he can
get sentimental sometimes.
He can. Really?
Certainly. Just three days ago,
when he and I were waiting
outside for you. It was odd.
How nostalgic. What is?
I once lived
in a castle just like this one.
He did. But when her.
Name was Elizabeth.
But I knew her as Liz.
He did say that he spent a
lot of time with that girl.
And you look so
ridiculous right now.
Your face is covered in powder.
How's that? No, it's even bluer.
I better go. Wash my face.
Soon. 15 years passed.
Liz's hair turned to pale gold.
Her freckles faded. She was
a fine woman, so I can tell.
You keep changing as she did.
Well, I really change.
It's impossible to imagine.
I'll probably just stay like this.
A scrawny, awkward scarecrow.
I wonder what kind
of person Liz was.
I bet she was beautiful.
She must have been
for someone like Chale
to say she was.
What's wrong with me? I'm jealous
of a stranger. But that's.
Absurd. Don't rub so hard
or your nose will come off.
It's you. And now you're soaked.
I don't have a towel.
Huh? What's wrong? Huh? Well.
I just be honest.
Huh? It's nothing.
Jonas. What do you want?
Looking to steal my work again?
Too bad it isn't done yet.
Why would I? My craftsmanship
is far superior.
I'll have you know
that I completed
my piece yesterday and so
did the other two. Oh.
Then does that mean you have
already shown them to the Duke?
Oh of course. And then can
you guess what happened? Mhm.
The other students were
told to leave at once,
and I alone
was permitted to continue
my stay here at the castle
when he looked at my work.
Do you want to know what
the Duke said? It shows promise.
Increase the accuracy.
You lose an now
even you can't
deny that the Thousand
Crests is as good as mine. That's
not true. Did you know I'm
the first person
they allowed to stay
in the castle after
presenting their work?
I dare say it's quite the honor,
don't you?
No one else can stay here. That's
what Dale told me. I refuse
to let you save your breath.
They gave me the honor
of moving into that tower.
Only the chosen artisan stays there and
you've got nowhere to sleep.
So try your best to make it
as a wandering merchant.
What was he trying to achieve
by coming here?
Is this some tactic
to crush my spirit?
He just wanted an opportunity
to brag. Really?
He can't gloat to his
friends now that they've left.
So he came to you? How absurd.
It's finished? Probably. What do
you think? Shall be honest.
It looks well made. Listen.
You did well. Scarecrow.
Not quite.
He's not happy with it.
But it's got
the right feel to it.
In that sense,
it's better than his was.
Make it more accurate than
it might be satisfying.
Move her to this tower immediately.
We have two artisans now.
There's no need to enlist
any more. Huh? Huh? Come.
So I'm sorry to ask,
but does this mean the Duke was
pleased with my sugar
confection? It wasn't clear.
Let's just say he
didn't quite hate it.
So you and Jonas Anders,
I believe
the two of you will be tasked
with creating
the peace he desires.
I've already sent
out some pages. They'll
make sure that your fairies
arrive here before too long.
I'll send for your things later.
Oh, thank you very much.
Didn't quite hate it.
You will get two meals a day
and use as much silver
sugar as you like.
We will provide
anything you need.
Should you find that you
require assistance,
you may simply
pull on this cord.
It rings a bell
in the servants quarters.
That way,
we'll know that we're needed.
What do I do when
I finish the piece?
You will pull it then as well.
Do you have any more questions?
And what are you doing in here?
I thought that I heard
a familiar voice above me.
And why are you in the tower, too?
Shouldn't it be obvious?
The Duke asked
me to so I can work
on the piece. But you.
Can't. So you are acquainted?
I did not realize.
Perhaps your fates
are intertwined in some way.
All I know is you're here because
the Duke has commanded it.
I can't believe I'm
competing with you again.
If you'd call the exhibition
a contest, then yes we are.
You can't win. You're no match
for my skill. You're a fool.
If you think you can
defeat Master Jonas.
Happy? Right.
We'll crush her. Yes. Of course.
I'll never lose
to the likes of you.
I won't lose either
to you or anyone.